{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "1. The isoelectric point of an amino acid is defined as",
      "answers": {
        "a": "pH where amino acids carboxyl group is uncharged",
        "b": "pH of maximum electrophoretic mobility",
        "c": "pH where amino acids amino group is uncharged",
        "d": "pH where amino acid has a net charge of zero"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. Which of the following amino acids has a net negative charge at physiologic pH (~7.4)?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Alanine",
        "b": "Histidine",
        "c": "Glutamic acid",
        "d": "Glutamine"
      },
    
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. Which of the following properties of a protein is least likely to be affected by changes in pH?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Primary structure",
        "b": "Secondary structure",
        "c": "Net charge",
        "d": "Tertiary structure"
      },
    
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. If a DNA sample contains 18% C on a molar basis. What will be the molar percentage of A, G, and T respectively? ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "32,18,32",
        "b": "18,32,32",
        "c": "32,18,18",
        "d": "32,32,18"
      },
    
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. Electrophoretic separation at pH 6 of a sample of protein A (M.W 25 kDa) , protein B (M.W  10 kDa) and protein C 3 (M.W 65 kDa) would result in which of the following? (Note: the isoelectric point of each protein occurs at pH 6) ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Protein A would move the farthest",
        "b": "Protein B would move the farthest",
        "c": "Protein C would move the farthest",
        "d": "None of the protein would move"
      },
    
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "6. What type of bonds are formed between two amino acids?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Glycosidic bond",
        "b": "Ester linkage",
        "c": "Phosphodiester bond",
        "d": "Peptide bond"
      },
    
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Which of the following methods can we use to check molecular weight of our protein?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "SDS PAGE",
        "b": "Mass spectrometry",
        "c": "Analytical SEC",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
    
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "8. In terms of DNA and RNA structure, what is a nucleotide?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "A nucleotide is a heterocyclic base ",
        "b": "A nucleotide is a sugar molecule covalently bonded to a heterocyclic base ",
        "c": "A nucleotide is a sugar molecule bonded to phosphate group/s and a heterocyclic base ",
        "d": "A nucleotide is a heterocyclic base bonded to phosphate group/s"
      },
    
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "9. The melting temperature of a nucleic acid:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Is directly proportional to the sum of the percentages of adenine and thymine ",
        "b": "Is directly proportional to the sum of the percentages of adenine and guanine",
        "c": "Is directly proportional to the sum of the percentages of thymine and cytosine ",
        "d": "Is directly proportional to the sum of the percentages of cytosine and guanine "
      },
    
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "10. Which of the following techniques cannot be used to quantify affinity between an enzyme and its peptide substrate? ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "X-ray crystallography ",
        "b": "Isothermal calorimetry",
        "c": "Surface plasmon resonance",
        "d": "Fluorescence anisotropy"
      },
    
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
  ]
}
